export const math_elements_coaching_phase_2 = [
    {
        choices: ["The difference between actual IPC and IPC absorbed", "The difference between actual IPC and IPC volume adjusted budget", "The IPC volume adjusted budget minus the local IPC absorbed.", "The IPC volume adjusted budget [fixed + volume (variable IPC rate)]."],
        correctAnswer: "The difference between actual IPC and IPC volume adjusted budget",
        question: "What is the indirect product cost of (IPC) spending variance?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Compound interest", "Simple interest", "Effective interest", "Nominal interest"],
        correctAnswer: "Effective interest",
        question: "The actual interest earned by a given principal is known as:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["3 sq. rt. of 3", "sq. rt. of 3", "2 sq. rt. of 3", "4 sq. rt of 3"],
        correctAnswer: "4 sq. rt of 3",
        question: "The vertex of an equilateral triangle has coordinates of A (0,0), B (8,0), and C (4,y). Find the value of y.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Join bond", "Debenture bond", "Mortgage bond", "Collateral trust bond"],
        correctAnswer: "Debenture bond",
        question: "A typeof bond, without any security behind them except a promise to pay by the issuing corporation is known as:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Explementary angles", "Elementary angles", "Supplementary angles", "Complimentary angles"],
        correctAnswer: "Explementary angles",
        question: "Two angles whose sum is 360º is called:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["3.5 seconds", "1.5 seconds", "4.5 seconds", "2.5 seconds"],
        correctAnswer: "3.5 seconds",
        question: "A ball is dropped from a height of 60 meters above the ground. How long does it take to hit the ground?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["P1,449.12", "P1,559.12", "P1,669.12", "P1,339.12"],
        correctAnswer: "P1,449.12",
        question: "A man owes P500, due in 3 years and P800 due in 7 years. He is allowed to settle this obligations by a single payment on the 6th year. Find how much he has to pay on the 6th year if money is worth 14% compounded semi-annually.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["180(pi)/x", "180/nx", "180x/n", "(pi)x/180"],
        correctAnswer: "(pi)x/180",
        question: "If at an angle measures x degrees, what is the measure in radians?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Binary operation", "Trinomial", "Polynomial", "Sequence"],
        correctAnswer: "Binary operation",
        question: "A mathematical method that combines two numbers, quantities, etc., to give a third quantity. An example is the mmultiplication of two numbesr in arithmetic.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Different equivalent uniform annual cash flows", "Identical salvage values.", "Identical equivalent uniform annual cash flows.", "Different salvage values."],
        correctAnswer: "Different equivalent uniform annual cash flows",
        question: "What must two investments with the same present worth and unequal lives have?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Between 100 and 1000 Hz", "Above 20,000 Hz", "Below 20 Hz", "10 to 20,000 Hz"],
        correctAnswer: "10 to 20,000 Hz",
        question: "The audible sound frequency is in the range of which of the following?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["A straight line", "Projectile motion", "A cosine expansion series", "A circle in polar form"],
        correctAnswer: "A straight line",
        question: "The equation y = a1 + a2x is an algebraic expression for which of the following choices?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["1", "4", "2", "3"],
        correctAnswer: "1",
        question: "Given f(x) = 5 / (x - 2) and g(x) = 2x + 1. Find the composite function f of function g, (f•g)(3)",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Translation of axes", "Notation of axes", "Relocation of axes", "Reversal of axes"],
        correctAnswer: "Translation of axes",
        question: "In the problem of writing the equation of a certain curve with respect to another axes in which the new axes are parallel to the original axes and similarly directed is known as:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["British thermal unit", "Energy", "Calorie", "Specific heat"],
        correctAnswer: "British thermal unit",
        question: "The quantity of heat required to raise the temperature of one pound mass of water through one degree Fahrenheit is known as:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["3, 4", "5, 3", "2, 5", "2, 4"],
        correctAnswer: "2, 4",
        question: "Solve for x in the equation: 2 log x = log 2 + log (3x - 4).",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["A series of uniform amounts over a period of time", "An annual repayment of a loan", "The present worth of a future amount", "The future worth of a present amount"],
        correctAnswer: "A series of uniform amounts over a period of time",
        question: "What is an annuity?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["P674.71", "P700.00", "P476.17", "P746.71"],
        correctAnswer: "P476.17",
        question: "Determine the amount that must be deposited every 3 months in a fund paying 12% compounded quarterly in order to have P25,000 in 8 years.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Dolo incidence", "Dolo causante", "Mora acipiende", "Mora solvendi"],
        correctAnswer: "Mora acipiende",
        question: "The delay on the part of the creditor to accept the performance of an obligation.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Bernoulli&amp;amp;#39;s Energy Theorem", "Pascal&amp;amp;#39;s Theorem", "Fluid Theory", "Hydraulic Theorem"],
        correctAnswer: "Bernoulli&amp;amp;#39;s Energy Theorem",
        question: "Any two points along a streamline in an ideal fluid in steady flow, the sum of the pressure, the potential energy per unit volume and the kinetic energy per unit volume has the same value. This concept is known as the:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["0.638", "0.567", "0.235", "0.568"],
        correctAnswer: "0.568",
        question: "Find the surface area generated by rotating the portion of the curve y = x^3/3 from x = 0 to x = 1 about the x-axis.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["-4", "-2", "2", "4"],
        correctAnswer: "-4",
        question: "Determine the slope of the curve y = -x^2 at the point (2,3).",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["The wave will travel faster", "The wave frequency decreases", "The wave amplitude increases", "The wave frequency increases"],
        correctAnswer: "The wave amplitude increases",
        question: "When a mouth organ is blown harder, which one of the following changes occurs in the characteristic of the sound wave?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["The weight of the atoms", "The electrons, particularly the outermost one", "The magnitude of electrical charge of protons.", "The weight of the protons"],
        correctAnswer: "The electrons, particularly the outermost one",
        question: "Which of the following affects most of the electrical and thermal properties of materials?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Electrons with positive charge.", "The K-quantum shell electrons.", "The outer shell electrons.", "The electrons of complete quantum shells."],
        correctAnswer: "The outer shell electrons.",
        question: "What are the valence electrons?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Euclid", "Thailus", "Torrecilli", "Bernoulli-Euler"],
        correctAnswer: "Bernoulli-Euler",
        question: "A law, which states that a curvature of the central fiber is proportional to the bending moment in homogeneous bar.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Downtime pay", "Moon lighting", "Check-in-pay", "Feather bidding"],
        correctAnswer: "Downtime pay",
        question: "A situation whereby payment is made for work not done. The term also applies to the case where more workers are used than a reasonable requirement for efficient operation.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["272 700", "227 700", "277 200", "200 277"],
        correctAnswer: "277 200",
        question: "How many permutation can be made out of the letters of the word ENGINEERING?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["522 km", "215 km", "252 km", "225 km"],
        correctAnswer: "225 km",
        question: "A man left Sta. Rosa City to drive to Lopez, Quezon at 6:15 p.m. and arrived at 11:45 p.m. If he averaged 50 kph and stopped 1 hour for dinner, how far is Lopez, Quezon from Sta. Rosa City?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Inductance", "Resonance", "Resistance", "Conductance"],
        correctAnswer: "Conductance",
        question: "In electrical circuits, how do you call the reciprocal of resistance?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["3s/(s² - 9)", "s/(s² - 9)", "2s/(s² - 9)", "s/(s² - 3)"],
        correctAnswer: "s/(s² - 9)",
        question: "The laplace transform of cosh 3t is:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Physical life", "Write off period", "Economic life", "Salvage life"],
        correctAnswer: "Write off period",
        question: "The lenght of time at which the original cost of capital used to purchase a unit has already been recovered.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Plastic", "Glass", "Rubber", "Metal"],
        correctAnswer: "Metal",
        question: "Which of the following is not a viscoelastic material?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["55 °F", "50 °F", "58 °F", "59 °F"],
        correctAnswer: "58 °F",
        question: "At 9 am., a thermometer reading 70°F is taken outside where the temperature is15°F. At 9:05 am, the thermometer reading is at 45°F. At 9:10am, the thermometer is taken back indoors where the temperature is fixed at 70°F, find the reading at 9:20 am.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["(pi)/4 (0.0001)^2", "(pi)/4 (0.00001)^2", "(pi)/4 (0.01)^2", "(pi)/4 (0.001)^2"],
        correctAnswer: "(pi)/4 (0.001)^2",
        question: "Which of the following is the equivalent of one circlar mil?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["The turbulent flow occuring above the airfoil", "The dragforce that increases that angle of the wing relative to the flow", "The increased velocity of the fluid above the air foil", "The reduce pressure above the air foil"],
        correctAnswer: "The reduce pressure above the air foil",
        question: "For an airfoil that is in motion through a fluid, the lift on the airfoil results from:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["31.82", "32.29", "29.96", "30"],
        correctAnswer: "32.29",
        question: "Compute the arithmetic mean of the following set of numbers: 18, 24, 27, 30, 35, 42, 50.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Dispersion", "Refraction", "Diffraction", "Reflection"],
        correctAnswer: "Dispersion",
        question: "The property of wave whereby waves of different frequency spread apart spread apart from one another.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["135", "120º", "108º", "98º"],
        correctAnswer: "108º",
        question: "Determine the value of each interior of a regular pentagon.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["30", "70", "50", "60"],
        correctAnswer: "60",
        question: "Given V1 = 2i + 3j -4k&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;           V2 = -3i + 2j + 3k&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;           V3 = 3i -5j + 3k",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["12/8", "3/2", "15/8", "9/5"],
        correctAnswer: "15/8",
        question: "Evaluate the integral of y^5 e^(-2y) dy with limits from 0 to inifinity.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["40, 50, 60", "10, 40, 50", "30, 20, 60", "20, 50, 70"],
        correctAnswer: "30, 20, 60",
        question: "A, B and C can do a piece of work in 10 days, A and B can do it in 12 days, A and C in 20 days. How many would it take each to do the work alone?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Complex logarithm", "Naperian logarithm", "Briggsian logarithm", "Natural logarithm"],
        correctAnswer: "Briggsian logarithm",
        question: "A logarith having a base 10 is called:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["25", "20", "22.5", "15"],
        correctAnswer: "20",
        question: "A 100-kg salt solution orginally 4% by weight salt in water is boiled to reduce water content until the concentration is 5% by weight salt. How much water is evaporated.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Both B and C", "The activation energy is less", "The molecules collide more frequently", "The molecules are less energetic"],
        correctAnswer: "Both B and C",
        question: "Reactions generally proceed faster at higher temperatures because of which of the following?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["18 fps", "15 fps", "12 fps", "20 fps"],
        correctAnswer: "15 fps",
        question: "A car starts from rest and has a constant acceleration of 3 fps^2. Determine the average velocity during the first 10 seconds of motion.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Tabular or roster form", "Equivalent form", "Rule form", "Equal form"],
        correctAnswer: "Tabular or roster form",
        question: "How do you call a method of describing a set where the elemts are separated by a commas and enclosed in braces?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Evaluation over different time periods.", "Differences in the magnitudes of the projects.", "Mutually exclusive projects.", "Use of the same discount rate for each period"],
        correctAnswer: "Evaluation over different time periods.",
        question: "When using a net present worth calculations to compare two projects, which of the following could invalidate the calculation?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["The estimated demand for the final product", "The transportation expensed for raw materials and products", "A description of a fabrication process", "Raw materials and Supplies"],
        correctAnswer: "The transportation expensed for raw materials and products",
        question: "The project engineering segement of an economic feasibility study will include all of the following except:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["1.66 x 10^-24 g/atom", "The mass is too small to calculate", "1 g/atom", "6.02 x 10^-23 g/atom"],
        correctAnswer: "6.02 x 10^-23 g/atom",
        question: "The atomic weight of hydrogen is 1 gram per gram-atom. What is the mass of a hydrogen atom?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["16/693", "568/25", "12/345", "56/12"],
        correctAnswer: "16/693",
        question: "Evaluate the beta function B (3, 7/2).",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["(1, 7/2)", "(-1, 4/5)", "(2, 3/2)", "(1, -7/2)"],
        correctAnswer: "(1, 7/2)",
        question: "Find the opint that is one-fourth of the distance from the point P(-1,3) to the point Q (7,5) along the segment PQ.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["0.375", "0.10714", "0.46667", "0.28571"],
        correctAnswer: "0.10714",
        question: "A bag contains 3 white and 5 red balls. If two balls are drawn at random, find the probability that both are white.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Money market", "Investment", "Earning value", "Authorized capital"],
        correctAnswer: "Authorized capital",
        question: "Grand total of the assets operational capability of a corporation&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Addition property of equality", "Transitivity", "Reflexive", "Symmetric"],
        correctAnswer: "Addition property of equality",
        question: "Given that a, b, and c are real numbers. If a = b, then a + c = b + c, what property is?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Sunk value", "Discount", "Salvage value", "Book value"],
        correctAnswer: "Discount",
        question: "The difference between what a negotiable paper is worth in the future and its present worth is known as:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["840 J", "480 J", "804 J", "408 J"],
        correctAnswer: "480 J",
        question: "A force of 200 lbs acts on a block at an angle of 28º with respect to horizontal. The block is pushed 2 ft horizontally. Find the work done by this force.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["3log_b 3", "2log_b 2", "2log_b 3", "3log_b 2"],
        correctAnswer: "2log_b 3",
        question: "Which of the following is the equivalent of the expression 2log_b (6) - log_b (4)?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["P 22,320.50", "P 22,302.50", "P 22,032.50", "P 23,022.50"],
        correctAnswer: "P 22,032.50",
        question: "The salary of an employee&amp;amp;#39;s job has five levels, each one 5% greater than the one below it. Due to circumstances, the salary of the employee must be reduced from the top (5th) level to the second level, the means of a reduction of P 3000.00 per month. What is the employee&amp;amp;#39;s present salary per month.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Ellipse", "Circle", "Parabola", "Hyperbola"],
        correctAnswer: "Hyperbola",
        question: "TThe general equation of conic is Ax² + Bxy + Cy² + Dx + Ey + F = 0. What conic section if the quantity of B² - 4ac &amp;amp;gt; 0.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["189.5", "189.5", "143.5", "145.5"],
        correctAnswer: "189.5",
        question: "Find the are bounded by points A(3,5), B(-2,9), C(-6,4), D(-5,-10) and E (8,-12)",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["7/2", "5/2", "5/4", "6/3"],
        correctAnswer: "5/2",
        question: "Find the sum of the infinite geometric series 2 + 2/5 + 2/25 + 2/125 + ... + 2/5^n + ...",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["8.25", "7.48", "6.00", "7.21"],
        correctAnswer: "7.48",
        question: "Determine the magnitude of the gradient at a point (1, 2, 3).",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["-273ºC", "0ºC", "273ºC", "-32ºC"],
        correctAnswer: "-273ºC",
        question: "What is the temperature in degrees Celsius of a molecule at absolute zero?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["10", "9", "8", "11"],
        correctAnswer: "10",
        question: "Tom can paint a fence 50% faster than Carl and 20% faster than Ted and together they can paint a given fence in 4 hours. How long will it take Tom to paint the same fence if he had to work alone:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Barrel", "Bushel", "Furlong", "Bar"],
        correctAnswer: "Barrel",
        question: "A US unit capacity used to measure soilds equal to 7056 cubic inches (0.1156 m^3)",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["80 ways", "50 ways", "60 ways", "120 ways "],
        correctAnswer: "60 ways",
        question: "How many permutations can be made out of the letters in the word DIEGO taken 3 at a time?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["30", "35", "40", "55"],
        correctAnswer: "30",
        question: "The radius of a circle which is escribed outside the triangle is 12 cm and its tangent to the 18 cm side of the triangle. The other side of the triangle is 24 cm, if the area of the triangle is 216 cm², find the 3rd side of the triangle.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Declining balance method", "SYD method", "Straight line method", "Sinking fund method"],
        correctAnswer: "Sinking fund method",
        question: "It is a method of depreciation where a fixed sum of money is regularly deposited at compound interest in a real or imaginary fund in order to accumulate an amount equal to the total depreciation of an asset at the end of the assets estimated life. How do you call this depreciaton?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Ampere&amp;amp;#39;s law", "Gauss&amp;amp;#39; law", "Ohm&amp;amp;#39;s law", "Kirchoff&amp;amp;#39;s law"],
        correctAnswer: "Ohm&amp;amp;#39;s law",
        question: "This law states, &amp;amp;quot;The voltage, v, across a resistor is directly proportional to the current, I, flowing through the resistor&amp;amp;quot;. How do you call this law?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["68,641.97 mm^3", "131,096.51 mm^3", "62,454.54 mm^3", "131,960.51 mm^3"],
        correctAnswer: "62,454.54 mm^3",
        question: "A cubical container that measures 50.8 mm on a side is tightly packed with eight marbles and is filled with water. All eight marbles are in contact with the walls of the container and the adjacent marbles. All of the marbles are the same size. What is the volume of water in the container?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Dew point", "Absolute temperature", "273 K", "Critical temperature"],
        correctAnswer: "Dew point",
        question: "The temperature to which the air must be cooled at constant temperature to produce saturation.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Organit matter is generally stable at very high temperatures", "All organic mater contains carbon", "Organic substances generally dissolve in high-concetration acids", "Organic substances generally do not dissolve in water"],
        correctAnswer: "Organit matter is generally stable at very high temperatures",
        question: "Which one of the following statements regarding organic substances is false?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["-2.25", "2.25", "-2.5", "2.5"],
        correctAnswer: "-2.5",
        question: "What is the sum of the roots of the equation: 2x^2 + 5x + 5 = 0?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["70 m", "36 m", "96 m", "85 m"],
        correctAnswer: "96 m",
        question: "An arc 18 m high has the form of a parabola with vertical axis. The length of a horizontal beam placed across the arch 8 m from the top 64. Find the width of the arc at the bottom.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Viscosity of the fluid", "Surface tension", "Air resistance", "Gravity"],
        correctAnswer: "Surface tension",
        question: "A leak from a faucet comes out in separate drops. Which of the following is the main cause of this phenomenon?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["4(9) 3/4", "35", "0", "3/4"],
        correctAnswer: "0",
        question: "Determine the first derivative with respect to x of the function: g(x) = 5[sqrt(10)] - 35.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["65 deg", "40 deg", "30 deg", "45 deg"],
        correctAnswer: "45 deg",
        question: "Find the smallest angle between the lines 2x + y - 8 = 0  and x + 3y  + 4 = 0&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Archimedes Principle", "Torrecelli&amp;amp;#39;s Principle", "Boyle&amp;amp;#39;s law", "Pascal&amp;amp;#39;s law"],
        correctAnswer: "Boyle&amp;amp;#39;s law",
        question: "If the temperature of a confined gas does not change, the product of the pressure and volume is constant. This is known as:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["28, 18", "12, 18", "24, 18", "10, 15"],
        correctAnswer: "10, 15",
        question: "Pedro is as old as jJuan when Juan is twice as old as Pedro was. When Pedro will be as old as Juan now, the difference of their ages is 6 year. Find the age of each now.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["mks system", "Absolute system", "Gravitation system", "cgs system"],
        correctAnswer: "mks system",
        question: "A system of units based on time length and mass is called:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["24 m/s", "28 m/s", "35 m/s", "18 m/s"],
        correctAnswer: "24 m/s",
        question: "A truck starts from rest and moves with constant acceleration of 6 m/s^2. Find the speed of the truck after 4 seconds.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Feather bidding", "Moon lighting", "Downtime pay", "Check-in-pay"],
        correctAnswer: "Downtime pay",
        question: "A situtation whereby payment is made for work not done. The term also applies to the case where more workers are used than a reasonable reuirement for efficient operation.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["2/5, -4/7", "-11/3, 5/3", "3/7, 5/6", "7/3, 5/4"],
        correctAnswer: "-11/3, 5/3",
        question: "The expression x4 + ax3 + 5x2 + bx + 6 when divided by (x - 2) leaves a remainder of 16, and when divided by (x - 1) leaves a remainder of 10. find the value of a and b.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Critical point", "Maximum point", "Minimum point", "Inflection point"],
        correctAnswer: "Inflection point",
        question: "If f&amp;amp;#39;&amp;amp;#39;(x1) = 0, then point (x1,y1) is called:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Forces present only in gases", "Forces not present in liquids", "primary bonds between atoms", "Weak secondary bonds between atoms"],
        correctAnswer: "Weak secondary bonds between atoms",
        question: "What are Van der Waals forces?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Matrix", "Boolean Algebra", "Laplace", "Elementary Algebra"],
        correctAnswer: "Boolean Algebra",
        question: "An algebraic expression having two variables in it. For example, 3x + y is called",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["200,277", "227,700", "272,700", "277,200"],
        correctAnswer: "277,200",
        question: "How many permutation can be made out of the letters of the word ENGINEERING?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["1", "0", "3", "10"],
        correctAnswer: "10",
        question: "Solve for x in the equation x^-1/2 - 2x^1/2 + x^3/2 = 0",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Radius", "Arc", "Circle", "Chord"],
        correctAnswer: "Circle",
        question: "A plane closed curve, all points which are the same distance within, called the center.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["20", "0", "60i + 24k", "5i + 2k"],
        correctAnswer: "20",
        question: "Given the following vectors: A = 3i + 2j, B = 2i + 3j +k, C = 5i + 2k. Simplify the expression (A x B)•C.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Amortization", "Investment", "Depreciation", "Depletion"],
        correctAnswer: "Depletion",
        question: "What do you think is the lessening of the value of an asset due to a decrease in the quantity available as a coal, oil and timber in forest?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["3/t", "1/t^3", "-2/t²", "-1/t^3"],
        correctAnswer: "-2/t²",
        question: "Given the parametric equations x = 4 - t² and y = t² + 4t. What is its derivative.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Crystal systems", "Monomers", "Polymers", "Isomers"],
        correctAnswer: "Isomers",
        question: "In molecules of the same composition, what are variations of atomic arrangements known as?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Tetrahedron", "Icosahedron", "Octahedron", "Dodecahedron"],
        correctAnswer: "Dodecahedron",
        question: "A regular polyhedron having 12 regular pentagons is called as:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["d²x/dt² + w²x = 0", "d²x/dt² - w²x = 1", "d²x/dt² + w^3x = 2", "d²x/dt² -w^3x = 0"],
        correctAnswer: "d²x/dt² + w²x = 0",
        question: "Eliminate the arbitrary constant B and a from the relation x = B cos (wt + a)",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["31.6", "22.5", "21.04", "21.5"],
        correctAnswer: "21.5",
        question: "Find the value of the soild bounded by the surface f(x,y) = 4 - ½ x² - 1/16 y², the planes x=3 and y=2,and the three coordinates planes.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Sunk value", "Salvage value", "Discount", "Book value"],
        correctAnswer: "Discount",
        question: "The difference between what a negotiable paper is worth in the future and its present worth is known as:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Elliminator", "Trisector", "Bisector", "Divisor"],
        correctAnswer: "Bisector",
        question: "the straight ilne or plane that divides a line, a plane, or an angle into two equal parts.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["P144,775.19", "P245,775.19", "P542,775.91", "P254,775.19"],
        correctAnswer: "P254,775.19",
        question: "A machine was purchased under these terms:&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;P30,000 down and P5,000 each month for 5 years. If money is worth 12% compounded monthly, what is the cash price of the machine?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["The luggage in the car impeeded its progress", "The headwind is too strong", "The speedometer is faulty", "The tires are underinflated, thus reducing the average diameter of the tires"],
        correctAnswer: "The tires are underinflated, thus reducing the average diameter of the tires",
        question: "It took longer that two hours for a driver to cover a distance of 120 miles even though the average reading on this car&amp;amp;#39;s speedometer was 60 mi/hr the most logical explanation for this delay is that:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["The charge increases the conductivity of the material.", "The charge is immediately lost to the atmosphere.", "The charge is instantly carried to the material&amp;amp;#39;s surface", "The charge is confied to the region in which the charge was placed."],
        correctAnswer: "The charge is confied to the region in which the charge was placed.",
        question: "Which statement about a charge placed on a dielectric material is true?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["15%", "5%", "7%", "10%"],
        correctAnswer: "10%",
        question: "In a survey concerning the smoking habits of consumer it was found the 55% smoke cigarette A, 50% smoke cigarette B, 20% smoke cigarettes A and C, and 12% smoke cigarettes B and C, only 10% smoke all the three cigarettes. What percentage of the population did not smoke?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["P193,912", "P199,312", "P139,912", "P183,912"],
        correctAnswer: "P193,912",
        question: "If a machine is purchased on installment and the buyer makes an P80,000 down payment and owes a balance of P150,000 in 2 years. Determine the machine&amp;amp;#39;s cash value if money is worthj 14% compounded quarterly.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Deviation", "variance", "Latus rectum", "Eccentricity"],
        correctAnswer: "Eccentricity",
        question: "What is the ratio of the distance between the foci to the distance between the  vertices in either hyperbola or ellipse?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["2.15 miles", "3.15 miles", "2.15 miles", "1.15 miles"],
        correctAnswer: "1.15 miles",
        question: "Find the distance along an arc on the surface of the earth that subtend&amp;amp;#39;s a central angle of 1 minute (1 minute = 1/60 degree). This distance is called a nautical mile. (The radius of the earth is 3960 miles)",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["653 miles", "316 miles", "416 miles", "170 miles"],
        correctAnswer: "416 miles",
        question: "A satellite orbiting the earth passes directly overhead stations in Pheonix and Los Angeles, 340 miles apart. At an instant when the satellite is between these two stations, its angle of eleavtion is simultaneously observed to be 60 deg at Pheonix and 75 deg at Los Angeles. How far was the satellite from Loas Angeles?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["P22,302.50", "P23,022.50", "P22,032.50", "P22,320.50"],
        correctAnswer: "P22,032.50",
        question: "The salary of an employee&amp;amp;#39;s job has five levels, each one 5% greater than the one below it. Due to circumstances, the salary of the employee must be reduced from the top (fifth) level to the second level, which means a reduction of P3000 per month. What is the employee&amp;amp;#39;s present salary per month?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Bookkeeping", "Profit and loss statement", "Accounting", "Balancing accounts"],
        correctAnswer: "Bookkeeping",
        question: "The process of recording all the transactions of the company, which afect any investment of capital so that tany time the results of investments, may be known as:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["7.634", "7.542", "6.351", "6.235"],
        correctAnswer: "7.634",
        question: "Find the length of arc of the curve y = x^(2/3) from point (1,1) and (8,4)",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Covalent bond", "Ionic and metallic bonds", "Metallic bond", "Ionic bond"],
        correctAnswer: "Covalent bond",
        question: "How do you call the strong bond between hydrogen atoms?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Pyramidal", "Square planar", "Tetrahedral", "Linear"],
        correctAnswer: "Tetrahedral",
        question: "What is the actual geometric shape of the methane molecule?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["It absorbs energy", "It becomes more negative", "It losses electrons", "It gives off heat"],
        correctAnswer: "It losses electrons",
        question: "A substance is oxidized when which of the following occurs?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Radius", "Circumradius", "Inradius", "Apothem"],
        correctAnswer: "Apothem",
        question: "How do you call a line segment from the center of a regular polygon to the midpoint of a side? It is also called as inradius, the radius of an incircle?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Dividend yield", "Equity ratio", "Price-earning ratio", "Operating expense ratio"],
        correctAnswer: "Dividend yield",
        question: "The index that gives ther ate earned per share based on current price per share is called as:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["56,563", "63,655", "66,535", "65,535"],
        correctAnswer: "65,535",
        question: "Determine the sum of the coefficient of the variables in the expression (2x + 3y - z)^8",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["y&amp;amp;#39; = (ysinx - cosy) / (cosx + xsiny)", "y&amp;amp;#39; = (ysinx + cosy) / (cosx - xsiny)", "y&amp;amp;#39; = (ysinx - cosy) / (cosx - xsiny)", "y&amp;amp;#39; = (ysinx + cosy) / (cosx + xinsy)"],
        correctAnswer: "y&amp;amp;#39; = (ysinx - cosy) / (cosx - xsiny)",
        question: "What is the first derivative of the given function xcosy + ycosx - 1 = 0",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["13.8 m", "12.8 m", "25.6 m", "20.8 m"],
        correctAnswer: "25.6 m",
        question: "Determine the distance between the foci of a hyperbola if the lengths of the transverse and conjugate axes are 10 m and 8 m, respectively.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["4:3", "5:3", "3:2", "8:3"],
        correctAnswer: "8:3",
        question: "If the daily wage of CPM and a plumber are in the ratio 2:1. In a day, a CPM has to work 8 hours but the plumber only 6 hours. Determine the ratio of their hour wages.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["P1,693.23", "P1,896.23", "P1,968.23", "P1,869.23"],
        correctAnswer: "P1,968.23",
        question: "What is the present value of P5,000 due in 8 years if money is worth 12% compounded semi-annually?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["x = 4 and y = x - 5", "x = 3 and y = x - 1", "x = 1 and y = x + 2", "x = 4 and y = 2x + 1"],
        correctAnswer: "x = 3 and y = x - 1",
        question: "Determine the vertical and slant asymptotes of the rotational function f(x) = (x² - 4x - 5) / ( x - 3 )",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Infinity", "4", "0", "8"],
        correctAnswer: "4",
        question: "Evaluate the Lim ( 2x² - 4x) / (x - 2) as x approaches to 2.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Ancillary conic", "Recursive conic", "Degenerate conic", "Rgenerate conic"],
        correctAnswer: "Degenerate conic",
        question: "If the graph of the conic equation turns out to be just pair of lines, a single point, or there may be no graph at all. The section is called:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Chord", "Cone", "Pyramid", "Quadrant"],
        correctAnswer: "Quadrant",
        question: "what do you call the one-fourth of a great circle?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["38 yrs old", "20 yrs old", "50 yrs old", "32 yrs old"],
        correctAnswer: "32 yrs old",
        question: "Five years ago the father is three times as old as his son. Ten years from now, the father will be twice as old as his son. How old is the son twelve years from now?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Registered bond", "Infrastructure bond", "Debenture bond", "Equipment"],
        correctAnswer: "Equipment",
        question: "This is a type of bond whose guarnty is in lieu on railroad equipment. What is this type of bond?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["tan 90", "0", "tan 0", "1"],
        correctAnswer: "1",
        question: "Wht is the value of (sin 0º + sin 1º + sin 2º + ... + sin 90º) / (cos 0º + cos 1º + cos 2º + ... + cos 90º)",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["4554 Joules", "3546 Joules", "3424 Joules", "2359 Joules"],
        correctAnswer: "3424 Joules",
        question: "A water tank in the form of an inverted right circular cone is 2 m across the top and 1.5 m deep. If the surface of the water is 0.5 m below the top of the tank, find the work done in pumping the water to top of the tank.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Dehydration", "Precipitation", "Saturation", "Hydration"],
        correctAnswer: "Precipitation",
        question: "dding more solute to an already saturated solution will cause the excess solute to settle to the bottom of the container. What is this process called?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["4.33", "3.23", "3.43", "2.33"],
        correctAnswer: "4.33",
        question: "If f(x) = x², find the average value of f on the interval [1, 3]",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["21 kph", "23 kph", "23.25 kph", "22.15 kph"],
        correctAnswer: "22.15 kph",
        question: "In an Olympic games, a team which participated in 1600 m relay event had the following individual speed. First runner, 24 kph; second runner, 20 kph; third runner, 22 kph and fourth runner 23 kph. What was the team&amp;amp;#39;s speed?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["240 ft", "180 ft", "140 ft", "150 ft"],
        correctAnswer: "150 ft",
        question: "A ball is dropped from a height of 60 ft. Each time it strikes the ground it rebounds to a height of 66% of the distance it fell. Find the total distance the ball travels.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["P 199,312.00", "P 183,912.00", "P 139,912.00", "P 193,912.00"],
        correctAnswer: "P 193,912.00",
        question: "If a machine is purchased on instalment and the buyer makes an P80,000 down payment and owes a balance of P 150,000 in 2 years. Determine the macine cash value if money is worth 14% compounded quarterly.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["oscillatory motion", "motion with constant acceleration", "motion in which the acceleration is proportional to the velocity", "motion with constant velocity"],
        correctAnswer: "oscillatory motion",
        question: "The motion described by the equation x(t) = A cos (wt - Φ) is:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Biaxial", "Billingual", "Binomial", "Bimodal"],
        correctAnswer: "Bimodal",
        question: "It refest to a statistical distribution having two distinct peaks of frequency distribution.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["2x + 4", "x^4 - y^2 + 4y - 4", "-2x + 4", "2x - 4"],
        correctAnswer: "x^4 - y^2 + 4y - 4",
        question: "Simplify (x2 + y - 2) (x2 - y + 2)",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["2/3", "4/3", "3/2", "3/4"],
        correctAnswer: "4/3",
        question: "If 4y = 3x, then, what is the value of 3x^2/4y^2?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["0.21", "0.3", "0.15", "0.2"],
        correctAnswer: "0.15",
        question: "what is the simple interest rate if an investment of P37,500 accumulates to P45,937.50 in 18 months?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["P505.90", "P508.90", "P605.20", "P550.90"],
        correctAnswer: "P550.90",
        question: "An Electrical engineer obtained a loan of P50,000 at the rate of 6% compounded annually in order to repair his mistress&amp;amp;#39; house. How much must the engineer pay monthly amortize the loan within a period of ten years?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Hydrochloric acid", "Carbon dioxide", "Sodium", "Helium"],
        correctAnswer: "Sodium",
        question: "Which of the following elements and compounds is unstalbe in its pure form?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Joint bond", "Debenture bond", "Collateral trust bond", "Mortgage bond"],
        correctAnswer: "Debenture bond",
        question: "A type of bond, without any security behind them except a promise to pay by the issuing corporation is known as:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["0.83095 m", "0.5 m", "1.5 m", "1.2 m"],
        correctAnswer: "0.83095 m",
        question: "A 5 meter extension ladder lean against the wall; the bottom is 3 m from the wall. If the bottom stays at the same place, how much should the ladder be extended so that the top would lean against the wall 1 meter higher?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["D (-∞, +∞), R (-∞, 2) U (7, ∞)", "D (∞, +∞), R (∞, 3) U (7, ∞)", "D (∞, -∞), R (∞, -3) U (-5, ∞)", "D (∞, -∞), R (∞, +5) U (6, ∞)"],
        correctAnswer: "D (-∞, +∞), R (-∞, 2) U (7, ∞)",
        question: "Let f(x) be defined by f(x) = {(x - 1), 5, (2x + 1)} for (x - 1) if x &amp;amp;lt; 3, 5 if x = 3, and (2x + 1) if 3 &amp;amp;lt; x. what is the domain and range?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Ergs", "Dyne", "Newton", "Kilogram force"],
        correctAnswer: "Dyne",
        question: "A net force that will give to mass of one gram an acceleration of 1 cm/s^2 is said to be:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Pay off", "Return on investment", "Break even", "Capital recovery"],
        correctAnswer: "Pay off",
        question: "What do you call the reprelacement of the original cost of an investment?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["The radius of gyration for a mass of uniform thickness is identical to that for ap lanar area of the same shape.", "Angular momentum for rigid bodies may be regarded as the product of angular velocity and inertia.", "Kinematics is the study of the effects of motion, while kinetics is the study of the causes of motion.", "The acceleration of a body rotating with a constant angular velocity is zero."],
        correctAnswer: "The acceleration of a body rotating with a constant angular velocity is zero.",
        question: "Which of the following is false?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Resonance", "Conductance", "Resistance", "Inductance"],
        correctAnswer: "Resistance",
        question: "In electricity, it is an ability of an element to resist the flow of current. What is this?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["siny = c siny", "cosy = c cosx", "cosy =c sin x", "siny = c cosx"],
        correctAnswer: "siny = c cosx",
        question: "Solve sinxsiny dx + cosxcosy dy = 0",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["(1.5,2)", "(1,2)", "(2,1)", "(1,1.5)"],
        correctAnswer: "(1,2)",
        question: "What is the minimum point of y = x +1/x?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["-8064 x^10y^6", "-8064 x^10y^5", "-9064 x^10y^5", "-8864 x^12y^5"],
        correctAnswer: "-9064 x^10y^5",
        question: "Find the middle term of the expansion (x^2 - 2y)^10?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["P144,775.19", "P542,775.91", "P245,775.19", "P254,775.19"],
        correctAnswer: "P254,775.19",
        question: "A machien was purchased under these terms: P30,000 down and P5,000 each month for 5 years. If money is worth 12% compounded monthly, what is the cash price of the machine?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["40", "60º", "30º", "90º"],
        correctAnswer: "90º",
        question: "The sum of two intereior angles of the triangle is equal the to the third angle and the difference of the two angles is equal to 2/3 of the third angle. Find the third angle.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Non-diagonal entries are all zero", "Diagonal entries are all zero", "Non-diagonal entries are all one", "Diagonal entries are all one"],
        correctAnswer: "Non-diagonal entries are all zero",
        question: "A diagonal matrix is a square matrix whose:",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Goodwill value", "Book value", "Fair value", "Market value"],
        correctAnswer: "Market value",
        question: "This is the amount of property in which a willing buyer will pay to a willing seller for the property when neither one is under the compulsion to buy or sell. What do you call this value?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["4x - y + 2 = 0", "3x - 2y + 3 = 0", "x + 4y + 2 = 0", "2x - 3y + 4 = 0"],
        correctAnswer: "4x - y + 2 = 0",
        question: "Find the equation of the line passing through the points of intersection of the circles x² + y² + 4x = 0 and x² + y² - 4x + 2y - 4 = 0.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["Regular polygon", "Concave polygon", "Convex polygon", "Irregular polygon"],
        correctAnswer: "Convex polygon",
        question: "It is a type of polygon in which each interior angle must be less than or equal to 180°, and all vertices &amp;amp;#39; point upwards&amp;amp;#39; away from the interior. How do you call this polygon?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["-2/5", "-5/2", "2/5", "5/2"],
        correctAnswer: "-2/5",
        question: "Solve the slope of the given curve x² + y² - 6x + 10y + 5 = 0 at (1,0)",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["11130 in^3/sec", "0.1257 in.^3/sec", "1275 in^3/sec", "11130 in^3/sec"],
        correctAnswer: "0.1257 in.^3/sec",
        question: "The height of the right circular cylinder is 50 inches and decreases at the rate of 4 inches per second, while the radius of the base is 20 inches and increases at the rate of one inch per second. At what rate is volume changing?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["24", "35", "33", "22"],
        correctAnswer: "24",
        question: "Evalue double integral of (3y - 2x²) dA of A is the region consisting of all poinst (x, y) for which -1 ≤ x ≤ 2 and -1 ≤ y ≤ 3.",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
      {
        choices: ["120.25 m", "110.12 m", "140.12 m", "131.81 m"],
        correctAnswer: "131.81 m",
        question: "If a stone is dropped from a ballon while ascending at the rate of 7.5 m/s reaches the ground in 6 seconds, what was the height of the balloon when the stone was dropped?",
        topic: "NA"
    }, 
]